Welcome friends to my channel
Stock Market Analysis. ICICI
Lord Group has declared its quarterly and financial
year 2025 results.
In this video, we will compare their quarterly
results and
analyze them in detail. We will also see
what ICICI Lord's management
said and their business metrics events
in the long-term perspective. So
friends, please watch this video till the end
because it will not only discuss profit and revenue
numbers but also the
actual metrics behind those numbers
in detail.
Friends, before I start this video,
if you have
not yet subscribed to this channel, please
subscribe to this channel and press the bell icon.
This will help us
in delivering our content to you in a timely manner and in
helping you take your investment decisions effectively. Friends, let's
start this video now. Friends,
if we talk about revenue,
in quarter one 2025, ICICI Lord had a revenue of Rs 5601 crore.  It
posted a net revenue of Rs 1.77 crore, which was Rs 4716 crore
in the same quarter of April to June last year.
If we talk about year-on-year
revenue growth, then the revenue
growth was 19%, whereas if we
look at the profit growth, then in quarter one
2025, ICI Lord had posted a net profit of Rs 580 crore,
which is Rs
390 crore in quarter one 2024 this year,
which was Rs 390 crore in the quarter of 2024 last year.
If you look at the growth in profit, then
we have seen a very good and healthy growth of Rs 49 crore.
Friends, if we talk about EPS, then
in quarter one 2024 last year, ICI
Lord had posted an earnings per share of Rs 7.95,
whereas in quarter one 2025 this year,
ICI Lord has posted an earnings per share of Rs 1.77,
which
shows a healthy year-on-year increment of Rs 48 crore. So, any
viewer who is watching this  For those who are
not clear about Earnings per Share, who
are new to the stock market, let me tell you
that Earnings per Share means
total earnings divided by total shares or
how much money your company earned in exchange for one share.
For example, if you
assume that your company earned a profit of ₹1
and the total shares of your company are 20,
then Earnings per Share will be 100 divided by
20, that is, it will be five Earnings per Share. The
company has not declared any dividend this time.
The Lord has refused to declare interim dividend this time.
Now let's come to the details of this
company. We know that it is an insurance
company, so it is
very important to look at the financial metrics properly. So,
their Gross Direct Premium Income
of the company was
7688 crores this quarter.
In the same quarter last year, it was 6387 crores. So, there has been a
growth of 20.4 percent in it, which  Industry
growth is higher than the industry growth of 13.3. So,
what is gross direct premium income? Any insurance
company collects premium
for providing insurance and later pays it out if there is
any problem. This is the income that
they get directly from premium. If
we remove processing fees and everything else, then the
growth of 20.4 in premium income
is very healthy growth because the
industry growth is at 13.3. Now, if we
say that excluding crop and
mass health, the GDPI growth of the company was
19.7 which was higher than the industry growth
of 14.8 in the first quarter of the current fiscal.
So, if we remove crop and mass
health insurance,
their GDPI growth also
came in at 19.7 which is a very healthy number
because the industry growth number was
14.8. The combined ratio
stands at 102.3.  Compare to
103.8 in the year ago period and capital gains
of 284 crores against 123 crores year on
year. Friends, now if we talk from a long term
perspective for their shareholders, the
company has achieved a compound sales growth of 17 per cent in 10 years and a
profit growth of 14 per cent in 10 years
and if we look at it in five years, the
sales growth has been 13 per cent,
profit growth in the last 5 years has also been 13 per cent
and the stock price growth has
also been 12 per cent. So if you see, their
profit growth and stock price
growth have been more or less on the same line,
hence the valuation of the company
is favorable, the company does not
appear to be overstretched. If we look at it superficially for the first time, then obviously
we are not providing you any investment recommendation through this video,
it is only for
educational purposes, so you
Do your own research and do
n't forget to consult a financial advisor. So friends, with this
I end this video. If you
liked this video, please subscribe to the channel and
like the video.
And if you want me to do a
fundamental
analysis and in-detail business analysis of a particular company, please
write in the comment section of this video and I will definitely make such a video.
Thank you, Jai Hind.